filezillapro.com 2019-07-09

# Privacy Policy - FileZilla Pro

Your privacy is important to us. This page describes the privacy policy applicable to the services using the filezillapro.com domain ( _the Website_ ) as well as the FileZilla Pro software products ( _the software_ ) as regards processing the personal data of users.

This information is provided to any entity having to do with the web-based and email-based services that are made available by Business Follows, the company that distributes FileZilla Pro.

When this policy mentions “Business Follows,” “we,” “us,” or “our,” it refers to the Business Follows company that is responsible for your information under this Privacy Policy (the “Data Controller”).

We are committed to respecting your online privacy and respects your rights for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”) you share with us. We do not record any personally identifiable information or information about the way you use _the software_ without your prior, explicit consent.

_The software_ may periodically and automatically contact the filezilla-project.org website to query the latest version of _the Software_. For technical reasons, the software’s version, your operating system name and the processor architecture of your system are being submitted. This data is being shared only with filezilla-project.org, the site dedicated to keep secure and updated all versions of FileZilla. For statistical purposes, anonymized data may be collected in aggregate form.

In order to extend our post-sale services and to inform you concerning promotional initiatives on the products you have purchased or similar ones, Business Follows may ask you to use your Personal Information provided during your purchase.

## **NOTICE**

**INFORMATION COLLECTION**

You may access and browse our Website without disclosing any Personal Information. However, if you attempt to purchase a product or service online, our payment gateway provider Avangate may request that you voluntarily supply it with Personal Information. Avangate uses a secure transmission method for all of its transmissions. Avangate receives and stores all information that you enter in their billing pages. You can learn more about their practices at their [privacy page](http://www.avangate.com/legal/privacy.php) and [GDPR compliance page](http://www.avangate.com/legal/gdpr-commitment.php) (Country: The Netherlands). Avangate does collect personal information you submit to them in order to complete transactions and if you opt for getting updates via email on the products or services you purchased. In the latter case such information is transmitted to us, utilizing Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software when receiving and transmitting any information.

**INFORMATION USE**

Business Follows is the sole owner of Personal information collected on the Website and of the Personal information you may voluntarily provide at the end of the purchase process if you decided to opt for being informed about product updates and upgrades. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to Third Parties. Business Follows will use the Personal information to provide you with product updates and upgrades, special offers, pricing information, newsletters, and any other information you request. At any time you can decide to revoke your consent to be contacted for these purposes, simply sending an email to privacy at filezillapro.com and requiring to be removed from the contact list. The data might be used to establish liability in case computer crimes are committed against the website; except for this circumstance, any data on web contacts is currently retained for no longer than one year from the date of purchase.

**INFORMATION SHARING**

We ensure that your Personal Information will not be disclosed to anyone other than a government institution or authority when required by law or other regulation.

**CHOICE**

You may choose whether or not to provide Personal Information to Business Follows. If you choose not to provide the Personal Information we request, you can still visit Business Follows’s Website, but if you buy FileZilla Pro you may be unable to get product updates and offers.

**SECURITY**

We have implemented security policies, rules and technical measures to protect the Personal Information that we have under our control from unauthorized access; improper use or disclosure; unauthorized modification; unlawful destruction or accidental loss. Business Follows utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) software when receiving and transmitting any information.

In addition, Business Follows protects your Personal Information off-line. All your information is restricted to our office. All employees and data processors, which have access to and are associated with the processing of Personal Information, are obliged to respect the confidentiality of our visitors’ Personal Information. Business Follows conducts background and credit checks on all of its employees prior to employment. Business Follows employs a User ID and password scheme in order to limit and achieve access to our computer network by our employees.

## **ACCESS/ACCURACY**

**ACCESS**

You may inquire about your Personal Information being held by Business Follows by contacting us via email (info at businessfollows.com) or mailing us at Via Catone 3, 00192, Rome (IT). Within a week, Business Follows shall provide you with a copy of the Personal Information that it keeps about you.

**ACCURACY**

To the extent that you do provide us with Personal Information, Business Follows wishes to maintain accurate Personal Information. Where we collect Personal Information from you on our Website, our goal is to provide a means of contacting us should you need to update or correct that Personal Information. If for any reason those means are unavailable or inaccessible, you may send updates and corrections about your Personal Information by contacting us and we will make reasonable efforts to incorporate the changes in your Personal Information that we hold as soon as practicable.

**MINIMUM AGE**

Business Follows does not request, or knowingly collect Personal Information from children under the age of 16. To ensure that children’s privacy is respected on our Website, Business Follows relies on Avangate policies and processes, requiring age verification on every inquiry.

**POLICY CHANGES**

Business Follows will make reasonable efforts to maintain an up to date and effective online privacy standards and policy. Whenever Business Follows makes changes to this policy we will post a notice of this change.

**COMMITMENT**

Business Follows takes all reasonable efforts to maintain up to date and effective online privacy standards and practices. We have linked every page of our website (“Website”) to this page for your convenience and you may also contact us via email at privacy at filezillapro.com or via mail writing to Business Follows, Via Catone 3, 00192, Rome (Italy) with any questions or concerns that you may have.

**ABOUT DATA MANAGEMENT AND PROTECTION**

Business Follows srl is both the owner and the controller. You can reach out to either writing to info at businessfollows.com or via mail at the following address: Via Catone 3, 00192, Roma (Italy).

The purposes of processing Personal Information data are related to post sales services, namely product updates and upgrades, special offers and customers’ surveys.

We take all reasonable efforts to maintain up to date and effective online privacy standards and practices. We have linked every page of our website (“Website”) to this page for your convenience and if you have any question regarding these privacy  policies you may contact us via email at privacy at filezillapro.com.

**PLACE WHERE DATA IS PROCESSED**

The processing operations related to the web-based services that are made available via this website are carried out the business Follows offices exclusively by technical staff in charge of said processing, or else by persons tasked with such maintenance activities as may be necessary from time to time. No data resulting from web-based services is either communicated or disseminated. Any personal data that is provided by users requesting to be kept informed about product upgrades and enhancements, special offers and customer surveys is only used to provide the service and/or discharge the tasks requested and is disclosed to third parties only if this is necessary for the said purposes.

**CATEGORIES OF PROCESSED DATA NAVIGATION**

**NAVIGATION DATA**

The information systems and software procedures relied upon to operate this Website acquire personal data as part of their standard functioning; the transmission of such data is an inherent feature of Internet communication protocols.

Such information is not collected in order to relate it to identified data subjects, however it might allow user identification per se after being processed and matched with data held by third parties.

This data category includes IP addresses and/or the domain names of the computers used by any user connecting with this web site, the URI (Uniform Resource Identifier) addresses of the requested resources, the time of such requests, the method used for submitting a given request to the server, returned file size, a numerical code relating to server response status (successfully performed, error, etc.), and other parameters related to the user’s operating system and computer environment.

These data are only used to extract anonymous statistical information on website use as well as to check its functioning; they are erased immediately after being processed. The data might be used to establish liability in case computer crimes are committed against the website; except for this circumstance, any data on web contacts is currently retained for no longer than ninety days.

## **COOKIES**

Some portion of Business Follows site may utilize cookie technology.

A cookie is a piece of data stored on the visitor’s hard drive containing information about the visitor that can only be read by the server that placed cookie onto the visitor’s hard drive.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. You can set your browser to block cookies entirely, delete cookies when you leave the website, notify you when you receive a cookie giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it, or limit the subsequent retrieval of cookies by the website. In addition, there are number of privacy-enhancing tools and software that will enable you to identify and block cookies on a selective basis.

If any third party operated services are listed among the tools below, these may be used to track Users’ browsing habits – in addition to the information specified herein and without the Owner’s knowledge. Please refer to the privacy policy of the listed services for detailed information.

**Analytics**

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behaviour.

Google Analytics (Google). Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. Personal Data collected: Cookie and Usage data. Place of processing : USA – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

**DATA PROVIDED VOLUNTARILY BY USERS**

Sending e-mail messages to the addresses mentioned on this website, which is done on the basis of a freely chosen, explicit, and voluntary option, entails acquisition of the sender’s address, which is necessary in order to send emails concerning product upgrades, special offers and customers’ surveys.

**PROCESSING ARRANGEMENTS**

Personal data is processed with automated means for no longer than is necessary to achieve the purposes for which it has been collected, that is, for the duration of the agreement (if the case be) plus for the personal details and, after that, limitedly to the purpose of defending the processor’s rights, for ten years after termination.

**DATA SUBJECTS’ RIGHTS**

Data subjects are entitled at any time to obtain confirmation of the existence of personal data concerning them and be informed of their contents and origin, verify their accuracy, or else request that such data be supplemented, updated or rectified (Section 7 of Legislative Decree no. 196/2003). The above Section also provides for the right to request erasure, anonymization or blocking of any data that is processed in breach of the law as well as to object in all cases, on legitimate grounds, to processing of the data. All requests should be emailed to info at businessfollows.com (Via Catone 3, 00192, Rome, Italy).

You additionally have:

  1. the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority ([http://www.garanteprivacy.it](http://www.garanteprivacy.it/);
  2. the right to withdraw consent at any time, without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal;
  3. The right to demand portability of your data to another service provider, where applicable;
  4. A right to be forgotten.
